The Viltrumites will always
be a threat to Earth.
When do we leave?
Andressa was a mistake.
I love you.
Not her.
Fuck you.
What was it you wanted
to tell me yesterday?
It was nothing.
He needs to go back.
[Oliver] You don't get
to tell me what to do.
[Telia] Lock down the bridge
and begin separation protocol.
- [Nolan] Where's Mark?
- [Oliver] I-I don't know.
[screams]
[Mark] You're never breathing again!
[Nolan] You two get to safety.
You can't win this fight.
[Lucan] Search everywhere!
[Allen] You were right.
This totally worked.
We left them there.
It is time.
[shudders]
[Thaedus] It is time for war.
We, the Coalition of Planets,
have never been more unified,
more determined, more ready.
And Viltrum has never been weaker.
Fifty Viltrumites hide behind
their conquered armies,
while millions of us
rise together against them.
Their coalition thinks it is strong,
but they will shatter before our strength,
our devotion, our vengeance.
They think they are our equals,
but they are not even
the dust beneath our heels.
We will end their cruelty.
We will end their atrocities.
We will end their tyranny.
We are endless.
Even the Scourge Virus,
the most depraved of their weapons,
only made us stronger.
We will repay
our suffering a thousandfold.
[Thaedus] They believe
that their strength is insurmountable.
[quiet, dramatic music playing]
But they are wrong.
Together, we have discovered
their weaknesses.
And we will use them
to break their hold on the galaxy.
[Thragg] There is no advantage
they have over us.
They will fall before our armies
as easily as they fall before our fists.
♪ ♪
[Thaedus] Decades of planning,
of strategy...
...of patience and unity and hope...
...have led us to this moment.
[crowd cheering]
There will be loss,
and there will be sacrifice.
But it will be less than the suffering
Viltrum brings upon us
every single moment they exist.
Remember always,
if we remain unified
against their empire of pain...
...we will prevail.
You know your tasks.
Go now and remember Argall's words.
[all] All is ours.
Let the war begin.
[triumphant music playing]
[suspenseful music playing]
[dramatic music playing]
[grunts]
[booming thud]
[Thragg] These animals
dare rise against us?
Against us, who brought
stability to madness,
brought order to chaos.
They are children crying for a freedom
they do not understand or deserve.
If they only knew
how the betrayer sacrifices them
for his own twisted purpose.
Thaedus and the Coalition
will be destroyed,
and Viltrum will retake
its rightful place in the universe.
I will not fail you.
[distant crashing]
[grunts]
[quiet, somber music playing]
[Oliver] This is bullshit.
Even Conquest deserves a--
He was a monster.
He almost killed me.
He almost killed Mark twice.
His devotion to Viltrum--
You weren't there.
You didn't see what he did to Earth.
People at home hate him
almost as much as they hate you.
What is it? Is he getting better?
He's strong. He should recover.
We need to get him out of here,
off this stupid planet to--
I don't know, somewhere with doctors
or a hospital or something.
We're deep inside Viltrumite territory.
Moving Mark would be too risky.
Better to stay hidden
- and wait for him to recover.
- But--
He'll pull through.
We just need to be patient.
How patient?
- Months, most likely.
- Months?
We don't have months.
We got to get to the war.
People will die
if we're not there to help.
- Oliver--
- I didn't leave Earth, and Mom,
just to be stuck on some stupid planet
with you.
[quiet, dramatic music playing]
It's just...
it's never been this bad.
Not even after
the first time with Conquest.
I never thought
I'd see Mark this messed up.
I wish he really was--
[quiet, emotional music playing]
[alert ringing]
General Kregg.
Lucan, Kradd,
divert to Glacia Prime immediately.
Our source reports
Coalition forces are en route.
They believe they can
wrest the planet from our control.
Ensure they learn their error
at great cost.
General, we still
have not located Conquest.
Or the traitor, his sons and their allies.
We will deal with your failures later.
Crush the Coalition's incursion
and you may yet
earn our regent's forgiveness.
[Lucan] It will be done.
- [Allen] Oh, my God. What are we gonna do?
- [Zoe] I don't know.
[Allen] What do you mean you don't know?
It's your game.
[Zoe] My armor just makes it up
from scratch every time we play.
Try going left.
[Allen] Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Wait, wait, wait. Hold up.
What did that Viltrumite just say?
[Kregg] Divert to
Glacia Prime immediately.
That's it. That's our way out.
What's our way out?
If they're headed to Glacia Prime,
that means we're headed to Glacia Prime,
and if the Coalition is gonna be there,
then we can hop off this tin can
and make a run for the good guys.
You said if we leave the pod,
those two Viltrumites
would tear us into tiny little pieces.
And pop our eyes out. Yes, I know.
But not if we get to the Coalition line
before that happens.
Then they get shot to tiny little pieces,
we get hot food and a shower,
and back into this war.
All right, let's do it.
Right after...
- We just finish this game.
- [video game beeping]
I mean, we're not there yet.
Couldn't even leave
right now if we wanted to.
[Zoe] No, exactly.
[gasps] Look out!
- [grunting]
- [hissing]
[intense music playing]
[screeches]
[gagging]
[groans]
Hope you're hungry.
Yeah, I'm never eating that.
[quiet, somber music playing]
So gross.
Just the liquid.
We don't want him
choking on anything solid.
♪ ♪
Here.
You need to eat, too.
I'm not hungry.
It's been weeks.
You'll starve to death
if you don't eat something.
I wish.
- [groans]
- Get up.
We're going training.
What time is it, even?
Training time. I just told you.
I'm good.
It wasn't a request.
[atmospheric music playing]
With all this time on our hands,
we might as well get you trained
and ready for the war.
I know how to fight.
Oh, you do, do you?
Yeah, I do.
Wonder why you don't know that.
Fine.
Show me what you've got.
[exciting music playing]
[grunting]
[straining]
- [Oliver grunting]
- [crunches]
See? A little training
might not be so bad after all.
- Maybe over by those mountains--
- [Oliver yells]
[Nolan] All right.
Feeling better now?
No!
I heard you that night at home.
With Mom.
What are you talking about?
I was upstairs.
You said...
You said you didn't love my other mom.
My real mom.
That she was a mistake.
I... I didn't mean for you to hear that.
Am I a mistake, too?
That's not what I...
Oliver--
I wanted to be just like you.
Like Omni-Man.
I even wear your stupid symbol.
But then you came home to find Mark
and didn't even bother to see me.
You don't care about me.
You never did.
You're right, Oliver.
I haven't been a father to you.
But I'm trying to do better.
To be a better person.
It's just...
It's harder than I thought.
You're too late.
[Zoe] This is it. We got it.
Come on.
- [video game sounds]
- We just got to get up there and...
Allen!
[Allen] Did you feel that?
I think we stopped.
Is there a way I can take
a look outside this thing?
Without you, like, suffocating?
Um... hold on.
[whooshing]
[Allen] Oh. That's perfect.
Uh, yeah, Zoe,
this is not gonna work for me.
I don't know how you guys see like this.
[Zoe] One sec.
[Allen] Okay, now we're talking.
Whoa.
- We're here.
- [explosions]
And so is the Coalition.
This is our chance. If we go now,
we might be able to reach
the Coalition lines
before those two nerds tear us apart.
Finally.
- [video game beeping]
- But we're so close.
I mean, we could probably finish
this level in, like, two minutes.
- Ah, it'd be so irresponsible of us.
- Yeah, we really should go.
[Allen] Okay. On three,
two...
[suspenseful music playing]
♪ ♪
[alarm sounding]
[Zoe] Allen?
[Allen] Shit. Come on.
[Zoe] I'm already at max thrust.
Wait. What are you--
[Allen] Just gonna give you a boost.
[Zoe] But what about you?
[Allen grunts]
[Allen] I'm over here, idiot.
[both grunting]
Oh, man. This sucked last time.
[Lucan] It also will "suck" now.
[all grunting]
♪ ♪
[Allen] Oh, I really hate this part.
Zoe! No!
[Lucan] Good. She returns to die, also.
[Zoe] Uh, I'm not the one
who's gonna get shot in the face
by an unstoppable superweapon.
[Kradd gasps]
[Lucan] Another time.
[Allen] Yeah. You better run. Or fly.
Whatever this is that we're doing up here.
Oh, man. You guys are the best.
[Zoe] I couldn't let you die.
Then we'd never finish the game.
[Allen] It's a good point,
and I still appreciate it.
- This battle isn't over yet.
- [distant explosions]
[squishing]
[Nolan] I know you don't like
how it looks,
but this is the best part.
[sighs]
[groans softly]
Shouldn't we, like, cook it or something?
- This one's better raw.
- [sniffs]
Uh...
[gags softly]
Mmm.
Ah. Ah.
Mmm. Mmm.
- Not so bad, huh?
- Hmm.
It's okay.
Is there any more?
You've always been
a picky eater, you know.
When you were born, your mom used to--
Don't talk about her.
[dark music playing]
But there's so much I could--
I said, don't talk about her.
[yawns]
What is it? Is he all right?
Mark isn't healing properly.
Why not?
[Nolan] All that liquid
we've been giving him
doesn't have enough protein.
We need to find something more nutritious
that he doesn't have to chew.
Those should do the trick.
You stay here.
Wherever there's eggs, there's a mom.
I need you on lookout.
Whatever.
[soft growling]
Uh...
It's okay.
[growling]
Yeah, yeah, I know you're all upset. Shoo.
[screeching]
[thud]
- [screeching]
- [grunting]
Thanks. [groans]
[grunts]
[screeching]
She's stronger than she looks.
And super pissed off.
You take the left, I'll take the right.
And watch for that tail.
[exciting music playing]
[snarling]
[Oliver grunting]
[Oliver and Nolan yell]
[Nolan] Okay.
Time to end this.
No.
She was just protecting her eggs.
Oliver, that thing's an animal.
Maybe she's smart
and we just don't know it.
We need those eggs.
She can't lay more if we kill her.
[dramatic music playing]
- You're right.
- [low growl]
[Zoe] Whoa.
[majestic music playing]
Yes, Talescria's pretty cool,
but wait until I take you to Little Unopa.
Oh, they have the best--
[Telia] Allen.
General Telia.
I thought I'd lost you.
I'll always find my way back to you.
You guys.
Mm.
[sniffles]
We should hurry.
Thaedus is waiting.
[atmospheric music playing]
You... you survived?
Sure did, sparky.
Wait. Why is that so surprising to you?
[distant roar]
I almost forgot.
There's someone else who wants to see you.
Traders found him floating in space
a full two sectors
from that Viltrumite prison
you and Nolan escaped from.
No. No way.
- [low growl]
- [Telia] He's been waiting here for days.
He refused to do anything
until he spoke to you first.
[growls] You.
You promised me more.
More battle. More glory.
More worthy opponents.
More!
Oh, it's good to see you, too, buddy.
Tell me, how do you feel about war?
[low growl]
It is good to have you back, Allen,
and thank you for joining our cause, Zoe.
You both are key to defeating the Empire.
Nolan and his sons,
are they also on their way to us?
They're not here already?
We sent out a rescue team, but you were
all lost deep in enemy territory.
Once the war started,
we had to call off the search.
It was too dangerous.
If Nolan, Mark and Oliver are alive,
they will find their way to us,
as you both did.
We just could really use them now.
Wait, are things bad?
What's happening with the war?
[Telia] These are the planets
still under Viltrumite occupation.
These are the ones we've liberated.
It hasn't been easy.
We've managed to advance in these sectors,
as well as over here,
but it's cost us a lot of good people.
Worse, they've pushed us back here,
here and here.
[sighs] We're trying
different strategies and tactics,
but the Viltrumites
and their forces are too strong.
Well, that is about to change.
- And don't forget--
- [Battle Beast roars]
What he said.
[atmospheric music playing]
I know we've been eating
the same thing every night,
but there aren't a lot of options
on this planet.
We can try to find
something different tomorrow.
Maybe go further afield.
It's not that.
I kind of love this stuff now.
If my mom meant nothing to you,
then why'd you have me?
Oliver, what I said about
Andressa wasn't true.
I was stupid and desperate,
and I didn't want to hurt Debbie
any more than I already had.
After I left Earth,
I was lost.
Andressa saved my life.
She and her people-- your people--
are so aware of their own mortality
that they don't have time
to dwell on the past.
If someone makes a mistake
but works to make it better,
they forgive and move on immediately.
They showed me there might be a way back
if I tried hard enough.
A bunch of them died because of you.
I know.
I know going to Thraxa was a mistake now.
But you were not a mistake.
And neither was my time with Andressa.
You deserve to be angry at me.
I've failed you in every way
a parent shouldn't.
And I know that fixing that,
if I even can, will take time.
Tell me about Andressa.
Tell me about my mom.
[♪ Oliver Tree & Whethan play
"Do You Feel Me?"]
[dialogue inaudible]
♪ Everybody knows
that I'm sticking it out ♪
♪ Everybody hates
that I'm feeling myself ♪
♪ Something made me think about it ♪
♪ Something made me think about ♪
♪ That's when it hit me ♪
♪ I'm not existing here ♪
♪ Nobody's listening ♪
♪ but I can hear you clear ♪
♪ That's when it hit me ♪
♪ I'm not existing here ♪
♪ Nothing came out when I opened ♪
♪ my mouth to you ♪
♪ Something made me think about it ♪
♪ I needed more,
something made me think about ♪
♪ what I'm coming for ♪
♪ Come on ♪
♪ Come on, do you feel me at all? ♪
♪ Do you feel me at all? ♪
♪ That's when it hit me ♪
♪ I'm not existing here ♪
♪ Nobody's listening,
but I can hear you clear ♪
♪ That's when it hit me ♪
♪ I'm not existing here ♪
♪ Nothing came out ♪
♪ when I opened my mouth to you ♪
♪ Do you feel me?
'Cause I'm feeling myself ♪
♪ Why don't you feel me? ♪
♪ When will you feel me, though? ♪
♪ So you don't feel me?
'Cause I'm feeling myself ♪
♪ Why don't you feel me? ♪
♪ When will you feel me, though? ♪
♪ Something made me think about it ♪
♪ Everybody knows
that I'm sticking it out ♪
♪ Everybody hates
that I'm feeling myself ♪
♪ Something made me think about it ♪
♪ Something made me think about ♪
♪ That's when it hit me ♪
♪ I'm not existing here ♪
♪ Nobody's listening ♪
♪ but I can hear you clear ♪
♪ That's when it hit me ♪
♪ I'm not existing here ♪
♪ Nothing came out ♪
♪ when I opened my mouth to you ♪
♪ So you don't feel me?
'Cause I'm feeling myself ♪
♪ Why don't you feel me? ♪
♪ When will you feel me? ♪
Hey, Dad?
How do you think the war's going?
You think we're winning?
If the Coalition has turned
some of the Empire's
conquered planets against them,
they might have a chance.
There's only so many Viltrumites
to go around.
[soft groaning]
Mark?
I'll ki... ki...
k-kill you.
He's just dreaming, but it's a good sign.
He'll wake up any day now.
- Any day?
- I know it's been a long wait,
but Mark is almost--
No. That's not what I...
[sighs]
I know we have to get back.
Back to the war, but...
I'm gonna miss it here.
How?
Grand Regent, we are in a unique
and precarious situation.
How?
Two primary reasons.
One, several planets
formerly of our empire
have joined the Coalition upon their...
liberation,
adding their numbers
to our enemies' forces.
Secondly, the Betrayer
has strategically deployed
several powerful allies,
combining their strengths
to defeat and kill lone Viltrumites.
Thaedus believes he has won this war.
That he and his allies are safe
on his adopted planet.
Regent, Talescria is too well-defended.
Is it?
Your words, our deeds.
[sinister music playing]
It is long past due for the Betrayer
to pay for his crimes.
With Thaedus and his allies dead,
the Coalition will dissolve.
And you, Emperor Argall,
will finally be avenged.
[Nolan chuckles]
Not bad, not bad.
[Oliver] Are you kidding?
You never even saw me coming.
Hell of a hit, too.
The Coalition's gonna be happy
you're on their side.
I'm glad you're here to help.
But let's hope we can end this war quickly
and get you both home as soon as possible.
I don't know if I'd call Earth home.
I mean, I miss Mom--
Debbie, I mean-- but...
- But what?
- I'm different from everyone else there.
Even Mark.
I made some new friends for a while,
but then I just outgrew them.
It was weird,
and they didn't seem to understand.
Uh-huh.
Once, Mom and Paul took me
to this seafood restaurant.
It had this tank full of lobsters.
O-Okay.
There was one in there that was beautiful.
It had, like,
blue speckles all along its shell.
It made me feel,
I don't know, fizzy inside?
Fizzy? You mean...
Oh.
Um...
I still ate it, though.
Huh?
[tense music playing]
[Mark panting faintly]
[grunts softly]
[exhales]
[groans]
[panting weakly]
[grunts softly]
[nearby whoosh]
- [Oliver] Mark.
- [gasps]
[laughs] Mark, you're okay.
Oliver.
Oh, I thought...
When I woke up
and I couldn't find you two, I...
I thought something had happened.
Then I found this.
I thought...
[breathes heavily]
We're both fine, Mark.
We're all okay.
You grew a beard.
Huh...
[laughs softly]
So did you.
You were out almost two months.
[gasps] Two months?
- But...
- Conquest.
You killed Conquest?
No. You did.
[grunts softly]
This is war.
And unfortunately, it isn't over.
[Thaedus] I know you have all
endured terrible hardships,
but our victories paint
an undeniable picture.
We are winning.
But at what cost?
Thaedus, we've already lost
more lives than we can bear.
How much longer must we beg
our people to suffer this bloodshed?
I understand your grief,
and I feel your pain.
Each loss in our struggle for freedom
wounds me deeply.
But I promise you, this is the only way.
And we must finish what we have started.
Our next course of action
is securing the gains we've made
- in the Geldarian sector.
- [gasping]
[low rumble]
[dark music playing]
[groans]
Ugh, what the hell, man?
[Zoe grunts]
[menacing music playing]
Leave no one alive.
[screaming]
[grunting]
Where is the Betrayer?
[Thaedus] Here.
[exciting music playing]
[both grunting]
- [high-pitched ringing]
- [heart beating]
[Telia gasping]
- [explosions]
- [screaming continues]
This is General Telia.
Scramble all available air support
and get our defense grid back up.
[chokes]
- [Allen] Hey.
- I told you.
Another time.
[both grunting]
[Zoe gasps]
[both grunt]
[Zoe straining]
[shouts]
Zoe!
[grunting]
Yes! Teamwork makes the dream work.
[Zoe grunts]
- [Allen] Zoe?
- [Zoe screams]
[both grunting]
[Zoe shouting]
Let's see you fight
without your Geldarian skin.
[Zoe groans]
[exciting music playing]
[Zoe laughs] Oh, you guys
are in so much trouble now.
These soldiers are enslaved.
Try not to kill them
so they can help us when they're free.
Got it.
[grunting]
Where's that air support?
Oliver, follow me.
What?
What are we doing?
Oh.
[both grunting]
[metal groaning]
[both shout]
No!
[dramatic music playing]
[groaning]
[grunts]
[grunting]
Viltrumites!
[both grunting]
- [groans]
- [Lucan yells]
[grunts]
[atmospheric music playing]
Yeah! Get the fuck out of here!
Uh, Mark?
[suspenseful music playing]
Ah, shit. Come on.
[straining]
[metal creaking]
[grunts]
[Zoe shouts]
[all straining]
[groans] Keep going!
[straining]
[yells]
[dramatic music playing]
[Telia] Our planetary defense
network is back up.
No sign of additional Viltrumite forces.
- [Thaedus] Good.
- [Oliver] Did we win?
[somber music playing]
Sorry.
Dumb question.
[grunting]
[gasps softly]
[cries]
Things like this...
aren't supposed to happen here.
This is only a minor setback
and shows how desperate
the Viltrumites truly are.
"Minor setback"?
Do you know how many people we lost today?
You must consider the war, Allen,
not the battle.
I'd really rather not.
[Telia] This doesn't make any sense.
Someone disabled
our planetary defense system,
but no one outside our network
would have been able to do that.
It's impossible.
The mole.
The commands all came
from a single console...
Oh, no.
[rubble shifting]
[grunting]
[screams]
Okay, shitbird.
Why did you sell us out
to the Viltrumites?
[grunts] What?
You let them in.
This is all your fault!
I-I-I didn't.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Your console dropped our defenses.
No! No, no. No, I-I-I would never!
Then who?
[shudders]
You.
How could you?
We dedicated our lives to the Coalition.
And you, you betrayed us all!
[Data Twin #2 crying]
I'm sorry.
How long have you been betraying us
to the Viltrum Empire?
Years.
I knew... I knew they were going to win,
and I-I didn't want to die.
If you don't want to die right now,
you'll tell us everything you know.
They're still going to win.
Shoot him again.
Wait!
Thragg's returning to Viltrum.
He's going to regroup there,
plan another attack.
- When?
- When all the other Viltrumites arrive.
He's calling everyone home.
Why... wh-why are you smiling?
If we strike Thragg now,
before he's joined
by his remaining forces,
we may have a chance
to end this war forever.
[Data Twin #2 crying]
Ugh.
Without their leader,
the other Viltrumites will scatter,
letting us deal with them one by one.
Wait.
You want us to go to--
The heart of their empire.
The planet Viltrum.
[dramatic music playing]
[dark music playing]
- [music ends abruptly]
- [wind whistling]
[dramatic music playing]
♪ ♪